Earlier, we talked about element-wise matrix
之前 我们讨论了对逐个元素进行的
operations.
矩阵运算
And that actually covers a lot of the math
这实际上包含了大量
involved with neural networks.
神经网络会涉及的数学运算
But when it comes to multiplication,
但是提到乘法的话
things can get a little more complicated.
就会有点难度了
Here, we're multiplying a matrix by itself to square its values.
现在 我们将一个矩阵与它自己相乘 得到它的平方
If you look at the answer, it's fairly obvious
如果看结果的话 很容易看出
where each value comes from, 1 times 1 equals 1,
每个值是如何得出的 1 x 1 = 1
2 times 2 equals 4, 3 times 3 equals 9, and so on.
2 x 2 = 4 3 x 3 = 9 等等
This element-wise multiplication is valid operation.
这种逐个元素相乘是一种运算
But most of the time when people mention matrix multiplication,
但是大多数情况下 人们所说的矩阵乘法
this isn't what they mean.
并不是这种情况
Instead, they're usually talking about a special operation
实际上指的是一种特殊的运算
called the matrix product, which ends up looking like this.
叫做矩阵积 结果是这样的
Now when you look at the answer, it's probably not so clear
现在看答案的话 可能不清楚
where these numbers are coming from.
这些数字都是从何而来的
Here's another difference.
还有一个区别
We said element-wise matrix math required
我们提到逐个元素矩阵运算
matrices of the same size.
要求矩阵大小相同
For example, this element-wise multiplication works fine.
例如 如图的逐个元素乘法是可行的
But if you tried to find the matrix product of those same
但是如果想计算这两个相同矩阵的矩阵积
matrices, well, you can't.
则无法计算
It can be confusing.
这是个很迷惑人的知识点
And you're pretty much guaranteed
而且当你开始
to mess it up at least a few times
构建神经网络时
when you start building neural networks.
肯定会出几次错误
But this is actually one of the most common operations
但这将是最常见的运算
you'll use, so it's important to understand.
所以一定要明白
OK, so how do we actually calculate
我们是如何计算
the product of two matrices?
两个矩阵的积呢？
Well, before we deal with matrices,
在处理矩阵之前
let's start with just two equal length vectors.
我们先从两个长度相等的向量开始讨论
One operation we can perform on these vector
我们可以对这些向量进行
is called a dot product.
点积运算
For this class, you won't need to know
对于这节课
how dot products are used.
你不需要了解点积的用途
But there's the link below the video, if you're interested.
但是如果你感兴趣的话 可以访问视频下方的链接
To find the dot product, we first
要计算点积
multiply the corresponding elements of each vector.
我们首先将每个向量的相应元素相乘
So the 0 times the 1, the 2 times the 7, and so on.
所以是 0 x 1 2 x 7 等等
Then, we add up all those results to get a single number,
然后将所有这些结果相加 得出一个数字
in this case, 180.
即 180
This operation basically let's us take two vectors of any length,
这种运算基本上可以计算任何两个向量
as long as they're equal, and convert those vectors
只要长度相等即可
into a single number.
然后将这些向量转换为单个数字
So how does that help us multiply two matrices?
那么这种运算可以如何帮助我们将两个矩阵相乘呢？
It turns out, to find the product of two matrices,
实际上 要计算两个矩阵的积
we take a series of products between every row
我们对左边矩阵的每行
in the left matrix and every column in the matrix.
与右边矩阵的每列求点积
That's really important to remember.
一定要记住这点
Whenever you multiply two matrices,
每次对两个矩阵相乘
you're actually dealing with the rows of the first matrix
都是将第一个矩阵的每行
and the columns of the second matrix.
与第二个矩阵的每列相乘
I'll go into more detail about why that's important later.
我们稍后会讨论相关的细节
But for now, let's work through an example.
现在先看个示例
To find the product of these matrices,
要计算这两个矩阵的点积
we'll start by taking the dot product
我们先计算
of the first row of the left matrix
左侧矩阵的第一行
and the first column of the right matrix.
与右侧矩阵的第一列的点积
For now, just ignore all these other numbers,
暂时先忽略所有其他数字
then we can pretend this row and this column are just
然后可以将这行和这列看成
two equal length vectors.
两个长度相等的向量
Now, we find their dot product, with corresponding elements
现在计算它们的点积 这行从左往右
moving across this row and down this column.
这列从上往下
So just like before, we have the 0 times the 1,
和之前一样 0 x 1
the 2 times the 7, and so on.
2 x 7 等等
The product between this row and this column
这行和这列的点积
becomes one entry in the result matrix.
计算得目标矩阵中的一个元素
You put it at the same row and column and indices
它索引的行数和列数与
as the row and column you just used to calculate it.
计算它所用矩阵的行和列相同
So since we used row 1 in the left matrix and column 1
因为我们使用的是左侧矩阵的第 1 行
in the right, the answer goes here in row 1 column 1
和右侧矩阵的第 1 列 所以答案位于新矩阵的
of the new matrix.
第 1 行第 1 列
If we had instead used row 2 in the left matrix and column 3
如果我们使用了左侧矩阵的第 2 行
in the right, the answer would end up here in row 2 column 3.
和右侧矩阵的第 3 列 答案就会变成第 2 行第 3 列
OK, all that work was just to find
所有这些运算步骤只是
one element in the new matrix.
算出新矩阵的一个元素
To get the whole result, we need to find dot products
要算出整个结果 我们需要计算
for every row in this matrix combined
这个矩阵的所有行与
with every column in this one.
这个矩阵所有列的点积
There are three columns in the second matrix.
第二个矩阵有 3 列
So that means we need three dot products
意味着第一个矩阵每行都需要
for each row in the first matrix.
计算三个点积
And since there are two rows in the first matrix,
因为第一个矩阵有两行
that means we'll need to find a total of six dot
所以对于这个矩阵乘法
products for this one matrix multiplication.
我们一共需要计算 6 个点积
We have one.
我们已经算出一个点积了
So to find the other five, we just
要计算剩下的五个
repeat the process for each row column pair.
只需对每个行列对重复相同流程即可
So the product between row 1 and column 2
第 1 行和第 2 列的点积
becomes the entry at row 1 column 2.
变成第 1 行第 2 列的项
Then, we finish off this row by finding the dot product
然后计算第 1 行和第 3 列的点积
between row 1 and column 3.
完成对这行的运算
We do the same thing for the next row finding
然后对下一行执行相同的计算流程
dot products for row 2 column 1, row 2 column 2, and row 2
算出第 2 行第 1 列的点积  第 2 行第 2 列
column 3.
第 2 行第 3 列
With all that done, we finally have
所有运算都结束后
the result of the matrix multiplication
最终得出我们想要的
we actually wanted.
矩阵乘法结果
That was quite a bit of work.
计算量很大啊
The answer matrix only has six numbers in it.
答案矩阵只有 6 个数字
But to find those six numbers, we
但是要计算这 6 个数字
did 24 multiplications and 18 additions.
我们进行了 24 次乘法 18 次加法
As your matrices grow, it gets even worse.
随着矩阵的增大 计算流程更复杂
I guess that's why we do stuff with computers, right?
我猜 这就是为何我们让计算机来完成这些运算吧
I mentioned earlier how there are
我之前提到
times when taking the product of two matrices won't work.
我们有时候无法计算两个矩阵的积
In the next video, I'll talk more about that,
在下个视频中 我将详细介绍这一点
and give you some important tips about matrix multiplication.
并介绍一些重要的矩阵乘法技巧